David is a adventure, drama, tv movie film directed by Robert Markowitz.
A distinguished military leader whose reign was touched by great
scandal, shocking betrayals and rousing victories.
A simple shepherd boy chosen to be king, under the
watchful eyes of prophet Samuel.
David, played by Nathaniel Parker.
Saul, played by Jonathan Pryce.
Samuel, played by Leonard Nimoy.
Batseba, played by Sheryl Lee.
Jonatan, played by Ben Daniels.
Abner, played by Richard Ashcroft.
David is a 1997 television film starring Nathaniel Parker as King David.
It was written by Larry Gross and directed by Robert Markowitz.
Shot entirely in Morocco, it originally aired at TNT on 6
April 1997 as part of its Bible Collection.
The film explores themes of rape, christianity, bible, religion, prophet.
The tone is emotional.